Where are Ning Emei and his Fengzi Battalion?
宁峨眉和他的凤字营呢
One li behind us. [*li: unit of length, equals 500 meters.]
跟在后边一里之外
When they're so far away,
可离你那么远
how can they protect you?
怎么保护你啊
We have Senior, don't we?
这不是有前辈吗
Xu Fengnian is quite scheming.
姓徐的小子心机深哪
He has transferred Fengzi Battalion away
他调开凤字营
because he expects assassins.
就是盼着有杀手出现
When you use your martial arts,
想看你出手
he'll know who you are?
从你手段猜你身份
Clever girl.
小丫头聪明啊
But he's got the wrong plan.
不过这小子打错了算盘
Fengnian, I'll only keep you alive.
我只保你性命
Even if all your subordinates are killed,
你手下死绝了
I won't care.
也与我无关
Fengnian should be out of Yongzhou, right?
凤年他们应该出雍州了吧
Upon their traveling speed,
从脚程上算
he should be.
该是如此
Out of Yongzhou,
出了雍州
they'll be arriving in Qingzhou.
就到青州了
Lord of Jing'an in Qingzhou
青州的靖安王
is always at loggerheads with us.
一直和我们北椋针锋相对
I'm afraid
世子在青州
His Highness will have some mishaps there.
恐怕会有些波折啊
Chu Lushan.
褚禄山
Here.
在
Don't go to the capital city with me.
你就不要随我去京城了
But I promised His Highness.
我答应过世子的
How many days does it take
你们轻装前行
when you travel light to Qingzhou?
到达青州需要几日
Two days only.
两日便可
You...
你啊
Stay by the gate of my mansion.
就守在王府门口
Once you receive the sword tassel carried by the hawk,
一旦收到了鹞鹰送来的剑穗
lead your cavalry
你立刻
to Qingzhou immediately.
率领本部骑兵赶往青州
Godfather, you want me
义父是要我
to invade Qingzhou?
马踏青州
No, or we would be rebelling.
那不就成造反了吗
Then what should I do in Qingzhou?
那我赶去青州该干些什么啊
Fengnian will tell you.
到时候凤年会交代给你的
What about you?
那您怎么办啊
Many people in the capital city want me to be dead.
京城确实有很多人想让我死
But once I'm there,
但我一旦去了那个地方
no one dares to kill me.
非但没有人敢动我
Instead, they'll do everything possible
而且他们会想方设法地
to keep me alive.
保我周全
Do you know why?
知道为什么吗
With North Liang Army around,
有我北椋大军在
you can live without any anxiety!
义父便高枕无忧
Here I go.
走了
Godfather.
义父
Who'll lead North Liang Army?
北椋军权交于谁手啊
No one can guard North Liang,
镇守北椋
but Chen Zhibao.
非陈芝豹莫属
Hawk.
鹞鹰
Sword tassel.
剑穗
Go fetch my bed.
把床给我搬过来
I'll be waiting here for the sword tassel.
老子就要在这儿等剑穗
I'm talking to you.
老子跟你们说话呢
Go move my bed here.
搬床去
Yes.
是
Quickly!
快去
Armor.
甲胄
Fujiang Armor?
伏将红甲
Grandpa Wei, you know him?
魏爷爷知道这东西来历
When I was as young as you,
我和世子一般年轻时
in this world,
天下
there used to be four Great Masters.
曾有四大宗师
One of them
其中之一
was Fujiang Armor
便是这南国
from the South.
伏将红甲
The man ahead of us?
前面拦着那个就是
But...
可这
When Fujiang Armor
伏将红甲人
assassinated the late emperor,
当年刺杀先皇
Cruel Cat Han Diaosi
被人猫韩貂寺
took off the Armor personally.
亲手剥了甲胄
His dead body and the Armor
这尸体和红甲
were hung on the flag for display.
都挂在旗上示众
It can't be faked.
这可做不了假
That's weird.
奇怪了
Where did he get this armor?
这红甲又是哪儿来的
Can he be the child of Fujiang Armor?
会不会是伏将红甲人的子女
No way.
不可能
There's only one Fujiang Armor in this world.
天下红甲只有一副
Now,
如今
the Armor should be kept in the Imperial Palace.
该藏在皇城才对
Let me try him out.
我去试试
You don't need to take the risk.
轮不到魏爷爷冒险
Shu Xiu.
舒羞
Lyu Qiantang.
吕钱塘
May I borrow your horse?
借马一用
As you wish.
随你用
Which one of us should go first?
咱俩谁先谁后
Shouldn't we go in turn?
出手也得分个主次吧
He's alive.
活的
Luckily,
还好
he's not Fujiang Armor Man among four Great Masters.
不是四大宗师里的伏将红甲
Who told you that?
谁说不是
Fujiang Armor
那这伏将红甲
should have been stronger.
应该更强才对啊
The Armor is from Mount Longhu.
这红甲出自龙虎
It's ancient armor.
是上古战甲
But few people know
可是很少人知道
that it can be divided into five armors,
这红甲可以分成五具
referring to five elements.
对应五行
Metal, wood, water, fire, and earth?
金木水火土
This is the Water Armor.
这是水甲
It's the strongest in the heavy rain.
大雨倾盆
They can't defeat him.
那两个打不过他的
Ask them to get out of the way.
叫他们让开
Stop.
停手
Come back!
回来
He's coming towards me.
朝我来的
It's over?
这就完了
When Fujiang Armor is divided into five bodies,
伏将红甲一化为五
they aren't as strong as the entirety.
确实不如归一时强悍
But they still can't be easily defeated.
可也不至于那么容易被击败
He isn't dead yet?
这都没死
A living death.
虽生犹死
He's not exactly a living person.
这已经不算活人了
Making Immortals Kneel.
一剑仙人跪
Is he a human
他到底是人
or is he an immortal?
还是仙
This old man is quite strong.
这老头好强
I'm afraid I can't defeat him.
我怕是对付不了
It's really hard to kill my brother-in-law.
小舅子还真不好杀
I can't assassinate him directly.
硬杀没戏
I'll wait for another chance.
再找机会吧
Luckily, I use the blade.
幸亏我练的是刀
Otherwise,
不然瞧见前辈
when I saw how you used the sword,
刚才这两剑
I would have psychological scars
怕是落下阴影
and never dare to use the sword again.
再也没有提剑勇气了
You don't use the blade very well, either.
你的刀也不怎么样
What do you think of that, girl?
怎么样啊
Not as good as White Fox.
比不过白狐脸
She's strong.
那丫头是不错
But far worse than me.
可与我相差甚远啊
She uses two blades much more beautifully.
人家双刀舞得比你好看
I can use the sword beautifully, too.
我也会漂亮剑法
She looks prettier than you.
长得也比你好看啊
Seriously?
这也能比啊
So, I won't be your disciple.
所以我不做你徒弟
Think no more of it.
别想啦
You are
你的天赋
as talented as Xu Fengnian.
真的不比外头那小子差
If you learn from me, you'll be a master.
若跟我学剑必成大器
Considering my identity,
我这身份
the stronger I am,
本事越高
the sooner I'll die.
死得越快
You're afraid that Xu Fengnian will kill you?
你怕姓徐的小子杀你呀
I don't think he wants that.
我看他舍不得
Bah.
呸
He's sinister and ruthless.
那家伙阴险毒辣
He can do anything.
什么事做不出啊
I can teach you.
我教你啊
Then you can defeat him.
保你胜过他
I won't learn.
不学
It's hard to learn martial arts.
练武太苦
Let me know when you want to learn.
想学的时候记得告诉我啊
Why must you teach me?
为什么非要教我
You're talented.
你天赋不错
And you act arrogantly.
还有那蛮不讲理的精气神
I like that.
也合我心意
What about him?
他呢
He has a good talent.
那小子天赋不错
But he's scheming.
只是心思太深
I'll keep observing him.
还得再看看
The two strokes
这两剑
killed him.
断了生机
But he looks alive.
可看上去还活着
The last breath, I'm afraid.
怕是最后一口气了
Dude,
兄弟
who are you?
你到底是谁
Why did you come to kill me?
为什么要杀我
Looks like he doesn't want to tell me.
看来是不想说
It's not that he doesn't want to tell you.
他不是不想说
He just can't tell you.
是不能说
Why?
怎么讲
I checked on him.
我看了
He's mentally disturbed.
这人神智受损
Mentally disturbed?
神智受损
But he was fighting normally.
刚才出手可不像
Look.
看
It's carved
整个甲胄内部
all over the inner side of the Armor.
都刻了
What's it?
是什么
As for the secret pattern,
其中奥秘
you have to ask that senior in your carriage, I guess.
就怕要问车上的人了
Look.
你看
What's this?
这是什么呀
A piece of armor.
那红甲人身上的
What's carved on this side?
这一面刻的是什么
It looks mysterious.
瞧着诡秘
I'm afraid no one knows it.
这世上怕是没人知道底细啦
It's evil of you.
小子心思不正啊
You're talking in riddles.
拐弯抹角来探底细
You know?
前辈知道
Tell us, then.
知道你就说啊
It's the genuine spirit.
这是真气
Genuine spirit?
真气
The pattern is carved with special material,
这符箓是用特殊材料刻下
for the circulation of genuine spirit.
作用是流通真气
Genuine spirit circulates through the patterns?
真气在这些纹路中流通
More than that.
不仅仅是流通
The patterns can also store genuine spirit.
还能储存真气
Most wonderfully,
最奇妙的就是
the patterns can transmit genuine spirit to this part.
这符箓将真气传入这里
Head?
脑袋里
So, the man out there
所以说外面那人
isn't born with superhuman strength.
不是天生神力
Fujiang Armor is vicious.
这红甲阴损得很
A batch of death guards
等于是
have been trained.
培养一批死士
Genuine spirit stored in the Armor
再用甲内储存的真气
can help them to kill.
助其伤人
That's why I killed that man.
所以我才下了杀手
Because everybody in the Armor
那里面的人
would rather die than surrender.
宁死也不会投降
(Unknown man) It's all right that we buried him.
人埋了也就算了
Why do we take away the Armor?
怎么还把那套甲带走了
(Unknown man) It's quite an evil armor.
如此手段
Let's study it.
研究看看
He said there were five Fujiang Armors.
前辈说这伏将红甲一共五具
But only one came to kill me.
虽说这次只来了一具
It's hard to say if the other four would come.
难保下次不会全都出现
Who told you only one came?
谁说这次只来一具
Three armors were waiting in the woods just now.
方才在树林里还有三具等着
Just now?
就刚才
Why didn't they come out?
那为什么没出现啊
They were scared of me, of course.
当然是怕了老夫了
Wait.
等等
Only four in total.
这样加起来也不过四具
Where's the fifth one?
还有一个呢
How do I know?
我怎么知道啊
Oh, no!
不好
Ning Emei.
宁峨眉
Your Highness.
世子
You were attacked?
遇袭了
a man in Armor attacked Fengzi Battalion.
有一红甲人偷袭凤字营
What happened in the end?
结果如何
I'm sorry.
是在下无能
More than forty soldiers were wounded or dead.
凤字营死伤了四十多人
But we failed to keep him.
都无法留住那个人
We only drove him off.
只是将其逼退
In the end,
最终
he ran away.
还是被他逃脱了
Please punish me, Your Highness.
宁峨眉甘愿领罪
I beg you
只求世子
to spare the remaining soldiers of Fengzi Battalion.
饶了凤字营剩余的将士
According to military rules of North Liang Army,
按北椋军律
how should generals and soldiers be punished
作战失利
for incompetence and failure?
是何责罚
Flogging is the least punishment.
最少鞭挞
Beheading is the harshest.
最重斩首
We ran into a man in Armor, too.
我们这边也遇上了红甲人
They two couldn't fight him.
他们两个对此可是束手无策
You've already done a good job
你能将其逼退
when you drove him off.
已是难得
Let me ask you.
我再多问一句
During the fight,
激战中
did anyone of Fengzi Battalion
凤字营可有
shrink back?
畏战后退之人
None of them ever shrank back.
一步未退
Fengzi Battalion's men die in battle,
只有战死的凤字营
but they never run for their lives.
没有逃命的北椋兵
Good point.
好
When half of you were wounded or dead,
死伤过半
but you still fought bravely.
勇战不退
You're indeed valiant.
可称骁勇之士
You fought bravely and won.
此战凤字营
You're not guilty, but meritorious.
有功无罪
You may rise.
起来吧
Thank you, Your Highness,
宁峨眉替凤字营
on behalf of Fengzi Battalion.
谢过世子
Take the remaining soldiers
你把剩余将士
back to North Liang.
带回北椋吧
Looks like
现在看来
I'm going on a trip to destruction.
此去东行怕是条死路
North Liang Cavalry is never afraid of death.
北椋铁骑何曾怕死
Shouldn't dead soldiers be taken home?
阵亡的士卒要不要回家
Take them back to North Liang
你把他们带回北椋
and catch up with me.
然后再赶回来
I'll slow down and wait for you.
我会放慢速度等你
It was a nice trick to buy them over.
收买人心的手段不错
It's hard to judge Ning Emei.
姓宁的不好说
But I think the other soldiers
剩下的兵卒
would like to die for you.
恐怕会为你战死
It's not that easy to buy over Fengzi Battalion.
凤字营没那么容易被收买
I don't want them to die, either.
我也不愿他们战死
You're the son of the Lord of North Liang.
你是世子
It's justified that they die for you.
他们为你死是天经地义
I take over North Liang,
我接手北椋
just to eliminate such justified things.
就是为了颠覆这样的天经地义
You're a weird man.
你小子有点古怪
Forget it.
不说我
Your sword moves were earthshaking.
前辈方才那两剑惊天动地
I can't help asking who you are.
我还是忍不住想问前辈名号
I use swords.
我用剑
You can guess.
你可以猜猜
Don't bother.
不用猜了
He's Li Chungang.
他是李淳罡
(God of Sword Li Chungang) How did you know?
小丫头你怎么猜到的
God of Sword Li Chungang?
剑神李淳罡
Sixty years ago,
六十年前
God of Sword Li Chungang was famous all over the world.
剑神李淳罡横绝一世
He used his sword Mumaniu
一把木马牛
to fight everywhere and no one defeated him.
战遍天下 未逢敌手
I've heard about your sword.
你的剑我听说过
I nearly forgot who I was.
连我自己都快忘了自己是谁
Who else could remember Mumaniu?
又有谁还能记得木马牛啊
So, you heard it.
原来你当时听见了
Sixty years ago?
六十年
How old are you now?
您今日几岁了
Those who practice genuine spirit live longer than those who don't.
修真气都活得都比普通人长
With Dahuangting in your body,
你小子一身大黄庭
you'll live longer than me.
将来比我还能熬呢
Now that you're the former God of Sword,
那既然是上一代剑神
where's your sword?
你的剑呢
Jiang Ni!
姜泥
What? It's taboo?
不能问吗
Nothing is taboo.
没什么不能问的
In the fight against Wang Xianzhi,
与王仙芝一战
he broke my sword Mumaniu
我的木马牛
with his two fingers.
被他双指折断了
He won?
王仙芝赢了
My sword was even broken.
剑都断了
He certainly won.
当然是他赢了
Then you're going to challenge Wang Xianzhi?
然后你要去挑战王仙芝
I just want to get back the sword box.
我就拿个剑匣
I don't have to challenge him.
不一定非得挑战他
You knew Xu Fengnian would visit Wudi City?
你知道徐凤年要去武帝城
I did.
知道
Then why are you still going?
那你还去
You think
你以为
I've been hiding underground
我躲在地下
because I'm scared of Wang Xianzhi
是因为败阵断剑
for losing to him and having my sword broken?
怕了王仙芝吗
Isn't it the fact?
难道不是
Losing a fight
打架打输了
never scares me.
有什么可怕的
I stayed hidden
我躲着
only because
只是因为
I realized that I was an idiot.
我发现自己是个蠢货而已
Your Highness,
世子
if we choose
咱们要是
to make a detour,
绕道而行
it'll take us less than a day to leave Yongzhou.
一天不到就能离开雍州
But if we go through the back of the mountain,
如果走后山
I'm afraid it'll take a couple of days.
恐怕要耽搁时日
I know.
我知道
Your Highness,
世子
is he
车里
really Li Chungang?
真是李淳罡
Yes, I think.
应该不假
What's wrong?
这都怎么了
Why are you so excited
一个名字
about his name?
变成这样
He's God of Sword Li Chungang.
那可是剑神李淳罡啊
Masters appear one after another in the martial world.
江湖代有奇才出
But he was the strongest for fifty years.
这一位独占鳌头五十年
His swordsmanship
他当年的剑法
was the best in the world.
那是冠绝天下
He was the coolest swordsman
这风采
in the world, too.
宇内无双
Girls were crazy about him.
真是令无数侠女痴迷
Other swordsmen admired him.
天下剑客景仰啊
Shu Xiu,
舒羞
are you crazy about him, too?
你也痴迷李剑神吗
I grew up, hearing a lot about his legends.
我可是听他传说长大的
To me,
对我来说
he's like the real god.
他就像剑神临凡一样
Qingniao, you don't look excited.
青鸟好像没反应啊
I'm a mere maid.
我就是个丫鬟
I love rich guys.
嫌贫爱富的
I'm not interested
对穷老头什么的
in a poor old man.
没兴趣
Lin,
姓林的
what about you?
你呢
Lyu Qiantang,
吕钱塘
I'm a scholar!
我好歹是个读书人
If he could be Number One Scholar,
他若能考上状元
I would admire him.
我便钦佩
Boring man.
闷葫芦
Let's hurry up.
咱们抓紧赶路
We'll live in the Taoist temple tonight
晚上住观里
where we can be sheltered.
遮风挡雨
Why do I feel the closer we get to Mount Qingcheng,
怎么感觉世子越到清城山
the happier His Highness looks?
就越高兴呢
How do you know here's a Taoist temple?
你怎么知道这儿有个道观
I divined.
我掐指能算
You're awesome, then.
那可真厉害
Your Highness,
世子
the Taoist temple
这道观
is a little bit weird.
有些古怪
How?
哪里古怪
Trees in the backyard
后院的树
have been cut down.
都被人给伐了
They were used
都用来
to make a fire.
烧火了
I failed to find the firewood.
当时找不到木柴
Then I cut down the trees.
就把树都给砍了
So,
原来
you came here, Your Highness?
世子来过
Three years ago, Old Huang and I lived here.
三年前跟老黄住过这儿
You once had a hard life.
你过得也不容易啊
Shu Xiu and Lyu Qiantang
舒羞和吕钱塘
went out for hunting.
出去捕猎了
Let's see
看看能不能
if they can take back some game meat.
搞些野味回来
It's good to have more people.
要我说还是人多好
When Old Huang and I stayed here,
上回我跟老黄窝在这儿
neither of us wanted to go out for food
饿得头都晕了
even if we fainted from hunger.
就没人愿意出去找吃的
Come over.
过来
Quick.
快
What?
怎么了
What's this?
什么东西
Let's knock them out.
砸人啊
Fengzi Battalion is away.
凤字营不在
Tonight is the best chance.
今晚就是最佳机会
Lyu Qiantang used to be a scholar.
那个吕钱塘之前不是读书人吗
Looks like he doesn't have great martial arts.
看起来身手一般
Let's take him down first.
我们就把他当作突破口
You know him a lot.
你倒是挺了解的
Have you heard me?
你听到我说没有
It's a deal, then.
就这样说定了
You even found the white chickens
清城山的白果鸡
on Mount Qingcheng.
这都被你们找着了
I'm getting a great feast.
这下有口福了
I'm glad you like it.
世子喜欢就好
Where's Lyu Qiantang?
吕钱塘呢
Out there.
在外面呢
He said he would guard the carriage.
说要守着马车
Ignore him.
不用搭理他
He always pulls a long face.
整天阴着个脸
How annoying!
看着就烦人
I want the drumstick.
我要鸡腿
Old Huang likes drumsticks, too.
老黄也喜欢抢鸡腿
Jian Jiuhuang?
剑九黄
I only know he's Old Huang.
我只知道他叫老黄
He's gluttonous and lazy.
好吃懒做
He's best at broiling sweet potatoes.
烤地瓜最在行
Come on.
来啊
Help yourself.
要吃自己拿
Why are you holding a stick?
手上拿根棍子干什么
To add fuel to the fire.
添把火
Ridiculous.
莫名其妙
Your Highness,
三年前
how long did you stay here with Old Huang three years ago?
世子和老黄在这待了多久
For a few days.
有些日子
Why...?
怎么
Why did you stay here?
会留在此处
We didn't stay.
不是留下
We were caught by bandits.
是被山匪抓了
Bandits on Mount Qingcheng?
这山里有山匪
Yeah.
是啊
They came, upon seeing the flare.
看见火光来的
They didn't kill you?
没杀你们
They were stupid bandits.
是群傻乎乎的山匪
Some were old and some were young.
有老有小
When they saw starving Old Huang and me,
看我跟老黄饿得不行
they gave us half of the roast chicken.
还分了半只烤鸡给我们
What good luck you had!
还有这样的好事
We became friends later.
到后来都成了朋友
When I left Mount Qingcheng,
离开清城的时候
they gave me a lot of food.
给我塞了好多吃的
You came back here
重游旧地
because you wanted to see them again?
是想再遇故人
I missed them a lot.
还真挺想见到他们的
If they see the flare,
若是能看到火光
they may come.
没准儿真会出现
Give us your money!
把钱都交出来
A lot of people here.
人还不少啊
- They're the stupid bandits? - Take out your money.
这就是傻乎乎的山匪
- Not them. - Give us your money.
不是他们
- It's weird. - Take it out.
奇怪啊
This is supposed to be their territory.
这应该是他们的地盘啊
- Your Highness. - Today,
世子
- I'm experienced in the martial world. - we'll get a lot.
我常在江湖行走
Judged by my experience...
依我的经验看
...there are two conditions
占山为王的山匪被换了人
where former bandits have been replaced.
就两种情况
How dare you chat!
还敢聊天
- You totally ignore me? - Yeah.
拿我当假人哪
Yeah.
就是
Take out your money!
赶紧把钱掏出来
- Take it out!
快点
Girls come here!
女的站在这边来
First,
第一种
- the former bandits were expelled. - As for men,
被夺权赶走
- What about the second? - we'll kill them all.
那第二种呢
They were all killed by new bandits.
被新势力赶尽杀绝
As for girls,
女的嘛
we'll enjoy them all.
我们一个也不浪费
Holding a dagger, girl?
小丫头还学着别人拿匕首
Sirs,
各位大爷
if I give this beautiful girl to you,
我若是交出这位美人
will you let us go?
能否放过我们
We're dying, anyway.
反正我们都要死了
May I ask you a question?
能不能再问个事
Where's Old Meng?
之前的老孟头去哪儿了
Cut the crap.
哪那么多废话
I'll kill you first.
待会我先砍的就是你
Shu Xiu.
舒羞
Your Highness.
世子
Don't let anyone of them run away.
一个也别让他逃了
Try harder to fight me.
都努力一点哦
Fight her!
给我上
Don't rush to leave.
别着急走啊
Come in and talk.
进来聊
Spare me.
饶命啊
I'm sorry I didn't recognize you.
我有眼不识泰山
Please spare my life.
还望大爷饶命
How long have you been in Mount Qingcheng?
来清城多久了
For more than a month.
一个多月了
In such a short time,
时间这么紧
you haven't built your own camp, have you?
没建自己的寨子吧
The former bandits left the camp.
寨子是原来人留下的
You killed them?
你把他们杀了
No, no.
没有没有
But I know
但是我知道他们
they were in trouble.
惹祸了
Trouble?
惹祸
What trouble?
惹什么祸了
Immortals of Qingyang Sect
青阳的老神仙
took away a teenage girl.
抓走了一个十几岁的小丫头
Old Meng and his men
然后姓孟的那伙人
went to Qingyang Sect, asking for the girl.
就去登门要人
In the end,
结果
none of them came back.
一个都没出来
Xiaoque'er?
小雀儿
Why did they take her?
青阳为什么要抓那丫头
I heard immortals of Qingyang Sect
听说青阳的老神仙
get stronger by hurting girls.
擅长采阴补阳
Maybe they just wanted that girl.
可能是看上了
When was the girl taken away?
抓进去多久了
Before we came here.
我们来之前的事
Less than two months ago.
不到两个月
What else would you like to ask?
大爷你还有什么要问的
I've confessed everything.
我都说了
How many people have you killed?
杀过多少人
None.
没杀过
We're poor men.
我们都是苦人
We didn't have a choice, but to be bandits.
都是被逼无奈干这个的
Grandpa Wei.
魏爷爷
Here.
在
There's a slope a bit further south.
往南不远有个小坡
The camp is behind it.
过了山窝就是寨子
Please go and check it for me.
麻烦魏爷爷帮我看一眼
All right.
好
Watch them carefully.
把人给我看好了
Don't worry, Your Highness.
世子放心
None of them can run away.
一个都跑不了
Where are you going, Your Highness?
世子去哪儿
I'm going for walk.
出去走走
I'll go with you.
一起
This is
这儿
Yin-yang Pavilion.
便是阴阳亭
It's said to be the boundary of Mount Qingcheng.
传说清城以此亭为界
It's the real world at the foot of the mountain.
山下是阳间
On the mountain,
山上
it's the nether world.
是阴间
It's hard to distinguish them, isn't it?
阴阳恐怕没这么容易分清吧
Yeah.
是啊
It's always hard to distinguish them
这世上本就是阴阳难分
and it's hard to judge people.
人鬼莫辨
Give me the writing brush and paper.
纸笔给我
Keep still.
别动
Your Highness,
世子
it's quite dark.
这夜这么暗
How do you manage
世子是如何
to see the mountain so clearly?
将山势看得如此细致的
I came to this pavilion before.
这亭子以前来过
I've kept
这景色
the scenery in my mind.
是记下来的
Where are you going?
去哪儿
I've drunk too much water.
多喝了点水
I'm afraid of the dark.
我怕黑
I need her to go with me.
得找个人陪着
What again?
又怎么了
When few people are around,
现在人少
we can sneak away.
正好溜走
We've got nowhere to go.
没地方可去
Come on.
哎呀
Don't waste time talking.
你别在这废话了
Go with me, anyway.
反正你先跟我走啊
I'll take the cat with us.
等我把猫带上
Your Highness.
世子
How did you find us?
您是怎么找过来的
I saw the flare
我看见火光
and I came to have a look.
就过来看看
How's the camp?
山寨那边怎么样
Many women were locked there.
关了好些女子
They were kidnapped.
都是抢来的
Their families were ruined.
都已经家破人亡了
Don't they want to take revenge?
她们没想着报仇吗
They do.
想
But they're scared.
可是怕
In the end,
最后
they all left.
都走了
Will we send the bandits
那些匪徒
to the government?
是送官吗
We're just kidding.
我们两个开玩笑呢
We're not running away.
我们不想逃
We just...
我们两个
Xu Xiao only asked me to protect Xu Fengnian.
徐骁只让我保护徐凤年
I don't interfere
其他人
with anyone else.
和我没有关系
Off you go.
你们走吧
I won't stop you.
我不拦着
Let's go.
赶紧走
Quickly.
走
Don't bother.
不用了
North Liang
北椋
isn't far from here.
离这里不远
If I run away,
我若真跑了
a message will be sent back by a carrier pigeon.
一只信鸽就能把消息送回去
You should at least try.
你总得试试吧
There isn't a chance.
没机会
Why do we bother?
何必徒劳
I don't think you want to leave.
我是觉得你不想走
You can hear us?
外面说话你能听到
I can whenever I want.
我想听见就能听见
What do you think, girl?
怎么样
Would you like to learn martial arts from me?
要不要跟我学武功啊
With martial arts,
有了一身本领
you can decide
走也好
whether you stay or leave.
都随你心意
I refuse.
不学
According to His Highness,
世子说了
the women are scared after they've been hurt.
被伤害的人害怕了
But it doesn't matter.
没关系
We'll take revenge
她们的仇
for them.
我们来报
What does that mean?
这什么意思啊
The women in the camp...
寨子里面的那女人的话
You can't believe them.
你可不能信
They're cheap women!
她们都是贱命啊
We've got a lot of treasure.
我们有很多金银财宝
I can give it to you,
都可以献给你们
as long as you let me go.
只要你们放过我
Dig holes.
挖坑
Why can't I blow out a sound?
我怎么不行啊
Let me teach you.
我教你啊
Xu,
徐哥哥
I knew you would leave.
我就知道你会走的
I won't leave until I teach you.
等教会了你我再走
All right?
好不好
Well,
那
come back and visit me later.
你以后要回来看我
I will.
一定回来
It's wise of you, Your Highness.
世子大才
You've kept in mind the landform?
这是把山势都记下来了
I shouldn't waste my trip.
总不能白走了这河山
They were killed.
人都杀了
Shu Xiu and Lyu Qiantang
舒羞和吕钱塘
buried them.
把人埋了
Mm.
嗯
What would you like to say?
魏爷爷是有话想说
Your Highness,
世子
why didn't we send them to the government?
为什么不把他们送去官府
The government may not kill
我送去的人
the criminals I give them.
官府未必会杀
The court always defends
跟北椋有仇的
the enemies of North Liang.
朝廷都会保
And of course,
当然
they're mere bandits.
这些只是些山匪
They're of little importance.
无足轻重
But just in case.
但我就是怕万一啊
They've killed so many people.
这么多条人命的仇
I don't want them to have any chance to stay alive.
不想让他们有机会逃出生路
Those bandits
那些山匪
deserve to be killed.
也是罪有应得
Not all bandits are so cruel.
不是所有的山匪都这样的
When Old Meng was here,
当年老孟头
he never killed people.
别说杀人了
When he met poor men during the robbery,
打劫的时候遇着苦命人
he even gave them money.
他还要自掏腰包
He robbed Old Huang and me when we didn't even have a single penny.
我跟老黄身无分文被他给劫了
When we left,
走的时候
he gave us a lot of money, instead.
他倒给我们好多钱
He and his men were righteous bandits.
那也算义匪
They weren't bandits.
根本就不能算是匪
They were just villagers who couldn't make a living.
只是活不下去的山民罢了
There were even the old and weak, women and children among them.
他们老弱妇孺都有
There was a little girl,
还有个小丫头
named Xiaoque'er.
叫作小雀儿
She kept asking me to teach her to blow the leaves.
天天缠着我跟我学吹叶子
She often stole jerky from Old Meng for me.
还老是偷老孟头的肉干给我
The girl
就是那个
who was taken to Qingyang Sect?
被抓去青阳派的小丫头
Wu Lingsu of Qingyang Sect
青阳派吴灵素
was bestowed Lord of Qingcheng
先帝御赐
by the late emperor.
清城王名号
He established Shenxiao Sect.
自立神绡派
It's a sect in the martial world
既武林门派
as well as the spy for the royal family.
又是皇室耳目
Mount Qingcheng is the first pass
清城是北椋
outside North Liang.
境外第一关隘
Actually,
这吴灵素
Wu Lingsu is spying
其实就是
on North Liang in the dark.
暗中监视北椋
I know.
我知道
I had planned
这次路过清城山
to avoid Qingyang Sect
本来打算好了
when I had to pass Mount Qingcheng.
要避开青阳派的
You did it right, Your Highness.
世子做得对
At present,
此时
we're fighting for the inheritance of the throne of North Liang.
正跟朝廷保世袭罔替
We can't have a dispute with Wu Lingsu.
就不能和吴灵素起争执
I promised Xiaoque'er
我答应过小雀儿
that I would come back for her.
要回来找她
She's been caught for two months.
被抓这么久了
It's too late now.
到如今什么都晚了
Yeah.
是啊
It's too late.
晚了
I can't save her.
救不了了
Put it away.
收了吧
To make a big difference, one must be patient
成大事者须戒急用忍
and weigh up the pros and cons.
权衡利弊
It's too late to save her, anyway.
反正人已经没法救了
I can
这账
avenge her later.
大不了将来再算
But what if she's still alive?
可万一人还活着呢
Your Highness,
世子
you should focus on our big plan.
大局为重
Grandpa Wei,
魏爷爷
I'm afraid I can't make a big difference.
我恐怕不是干大事的人
I'm going to break into Mount Qingcheng.
我要闯这清城山